Who's laughing now?
Terrifier 2 is a horror, thriller film directed by Damien Leone.
A year after the Miles County massacre, Art the Clown
is resurrected by a sinister entity.
Art returns home, where he must hunt down and destroy teenage
Sienna and her younger brother Jonathan on Halloween.
As the body count rises, the siblings fight to stay alive while
uncovering the true nature of Art's evil intent.
Art the Clown, played by David Howard Thornton.
Sienna Shaw, played by Lauren LaVera.
Jonathan Shaw, played by Elliott Fullam.
Barbara, played by Sarah Voigt.
Brooke, played by Kailey Hyman.
Allie, played by Casey Hartnett.
Terrifier 2 is a 2022 American independent supernatural slasher
film written, edited, and directed by Damien Leone.
It is the sequel to Terrifier (2016) and the second
installment in the Terrifier film series.
It includes the return of David Howard Thornton and Samantha Scaffidi, who portrayed Art the Clown and Victoria Heyes, respectively, in
the first film, and features Lauren LaVera, Elliott Fullam, Sarah Voigt, Kailey Hyman, and Casey Hartnett in new roles.
The plot follows Art's resurrection and pursuit on Halloween night of teenage
Sienna Shaw (LaVera), who discovers that she is destined to defeat him.
The film originated from a feature film concept Leone began developing shortly
after filming his directorial debut short film The 9th Circle (2008).
The concept of the planned film focused heavily on an
angel-dressed heroine and ultimately fell apart.
Following its predecessor's release, Leone wanted to bring the heroine back—she would evolve
into Sienna, someone Leone describes as the "heart and soul" of Terrifier 2.
Leone spent three months writing a character-driven screenplay following
criticism of the first film's perceived lack of narrative.
Funding was exacting as the script was more ambitious than
the first film and required a bigger budget.
Leone secured finances from private investors and Scotty Gelt Productions prior to filming, and he
launched an Indiegogo campaign with a $50,000 goal to produce a practical effects-driven scene.
The campaign was a massive success, reaching over 430% of the
initial goal with a donation total of $250,000.
It is one of the numerous films impacted by the worldwide COVID-19 pandemic, with
principal photography coming to a halt mid-2020 due to the pandemic lockdowns.
Terrifier 2 had its premiere at the FrightFest on August 29, 2022, and was
theatrically released in the United States on October 6, by Cinedigm.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, with particular praise for LaVera
and Thornton's performances, though the film's runtime received some criticism.
Many critics considered the film to be an improvement over its predecessor.
A sequel, Terrifier 3, was released in October 2024.
The film explores themes of halloween, clown, gore, resurrection, sequel.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and intense.